<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<GridViewExMasterRow>
  <doc name="class">
    <remarks>
      <para>
        The <c>GridViewExMasterRow</c> has the ability to display master row just above the normal row. For example
        you may have a query which retrieves goods received for any day, for a single day there may be many goods
        received and you want to prioterize receive date, then by making this particular column as master the
        <see cref="GridViewEx" /> will insert a master row above the normal rows diaplying the date and rest all the
        data for that date will be displayed just below this row.
      </para>
      <para>
        The property <c>DefaultSortExpression</c> of the <c>GridView</c> tells the grid that whether the grid specefied consist of
        MasterRow or not. If the property consist of $ then all the columns prceding this symbol will be considered as master rows
        As <see cref="GridViewEx/CreateRow" /> creates date row, if the property <see cref="DisplayMasterRow" /> is set to true
        and <see cref="MasterColumnIndexs" /> is not null it asks <c>GridViewExMasterRow</c> to create the row.
        <c>GridViewExMasterRow</c> hooks to <c>GridViewEx</c> <c>RowDataBound</c> event. When constructed, it hooks to the grid's
        <c>RowDataBound</c> event only if this is the first master row. <see cref="gv_RowDataBound" /> is called for each row in the grid.
        During this event, we check whether the current row belongs to us, it does this by performing html comparison. If it does,
        we increment our row count. If it does not, then the set of our child rows is final. This new row is the new master.
        <![CDATA[
        <jquery:GridViewEx ID="gv" runat="server" DataSourceID="ds" AutoGenerateColumns="false"
          AllowSorting="true" ShowFooter="true" DefaultSortExpression="lane_id;$;bucket_id">
          <Columns>
            ............................
            ............................
          </Columns>
        </jquery:GridViewEx>
      ]]>
      </para>
      <para>
        After one of the master is complete it is required to evalute sum for each master, which is computed by the function
        <see cref="InitializeSubTotals" />
      </para>
      <para>
        The deatils of master row and its value are stored in a List variable, which renders all the contents with in a master
        row. The method which performs the rendering for the master row header is <see cref="RenderMasterRowHeader" /> which
        is being called by <see cref="Render" /> event of the class.
      </para>
    </remarks>
  </doc>
</GridViewExMasterRow>
